

PAUL COWAN

• DETAILS •

Glasgow United Kingdom 7908771391 paul.cowan@cutting.scot

SKILLS

HTML

JavaScript

typescript

react

nodejs

d3/d3js

HTML, CSS

redux

SASS/SCSS

Angular

rxjs

SQL Server, MYSQL, POSTGRES

C#

ASP.NET MVC

RUBY

HOBBIES

Combat sports, boxing, MMA

LINKS

linkedin

PROFILE

My passion is and always has been frontend development. I love the instant visual feedback that is unique to frontend development.

I am an open-source fanatic with <u>over 140+ merged pull requests in the past 12 months alone</u> into many, many, many open source repositories.

I write professionally for logrocket and my own personal blog.

I have over 20 years of experience working on some exceptional frontend pieces of work for companies such as <u>waitrose</u>, <u>the Volvo ocean race</u>, the Scottish and Northern Irish governments and many others.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Developer Experience Consultant at frontside, remote

February 2021 — January 2022

Working as a developer experience (dx) consultant.

The role involved working with software teams who are more accustomed to backend programming and improving their frontend programming practices.

Frontend Developer Contract at Disclosure Scotland, Glasgow

August 2019 — December 2020

My second contract with Disclosure Scotland, where I worked on all things javascript/typescript related for Disclosure Scotland. From the <u>basic disclosure public</u> website to internal tools that the agents use to process applications.

- · react static and ssr builds
- typescript
- nodejs

Frontend Developer Contract at Screenmedia, Glasgow

June 2019 — August 2019

Front end react development for a client of Screenmedia with days on and offsite. I performed a number of R&D exercises or spikes to check the viability of proposed approaches.

- · react 16.8 with hooks
- typescript
- d3js
- azure
- docker
- lighthouse
- cypress

Data Visualisations at Continuity2, Glasgow

April 2019 — June 2019

Bringing data to life in the form of svg data visualisations using a combination of reactjs and d3js.

- reactjs
- d3js
- typescript
- sass

Contract Software Developer at Waracle, Glasgow, United Kingdom

January 2019 — April 2019

Full stack development for an online web portal with azure serverless technologies including blob storage and azure functions.

- Angular
- rxjs
- HTML 5, CSS, sass, Typescript
- Azure (Blob storage, functions)
- Terraform

Frontend Developer Contract at BJSS - Disclosure Scotland, Glasgow

June 2017 — December 2018

Rewrite of the old disclosure Scotland online application forms for criminal record checks into a react frontend written in typescript. Worked on other frontend systems for processing the online applications.

- · Reactjs with redux for state management
- · Jest, enzyme for Testing
- HTML 5, CSS, sass
- Typescript

Full Stack Contract Developer at WIPRO - Lloyds Bank, Edinburgh

November 2016 — June 2017

Working on the Scottish Widows pension portal

- · React including mobx for state management
- Jest for Testing
- HTML 5, CSS, Styled Components
- JavaScript
- Nodejs

Full Stack Contract Developer at City Holdings

 ${\sf March\,2016-November\,2016}$

Various projects including invoicing portal.

- Angular
- C#
- ASP.NET MVC
- SQL Server
- HTML, CSS
- JavaScript
- TDD (Jasmine, MSTest)

Full StackContract Developer at Continuity2, Glasgow

 ${\sf September\,2007-November\,2012}$

Often the only developer on the Continuity2 business continuity software suite.

- ASP.NET MVC (1.0 4.5) C#
- Backbone.js JavaScript
- SQL Server
- MSMQ
- Nhibernate

Full Stack Contract Developer at Twentysixlondon, London

March 2004 — August 2007

Working for a digital agency working on some reasonably sized websites such as waitrose and the volvo ocean race.

- C#
- ASP.NET

EDUCATION

ο Scottish Higher Maths – B, Further Education Anniesland, Glasgow

October 2015 — June 2016

COURSES

o

¶ REFERENCES

Richard McGlave from Continuity2

richard.mcglave@continuity2.com